Phone: (+44) 07910-390 599 Webpage: <a href="http://www.hentula.com">http://www.hentula.com</a> Email: joakim.hentula@gmail.com

Joakim Hentula 4 Hitchman Mews CV31 3QW Leamington Spa, Warwickshire United Kingdom

# Curriculum Vitae - Joakim Hentula

# **Objective**

Creating great games, working with talented people.

### **Profile**

A programmer with eight years of professional games development experience. Disciplined, hard working and with a knack for problem solving. Does not back down from a challenge and is able to learn, understand and apply new technologies in a well organized and efficient manner.

A naturally supportive team-player who has been told he's a great teacher. Positive, creative, listens well and most of all eager to work with and learn from talented people making great games.

## **Expertise**

- C++ (10+ years)
- Python
- C#
- Audio programming (in-house and AudioKinetic Wwise)
- Tools development (in house real time object editor, audio pipeline)
- Multi platform development (Xbox 360, PS3, Steam, TRC/TCR compatibility)
- Perforce
- Has experience in various audio (Ableton Live, Cubase) and visual suites (Blender3D,
   3DS Max/MAXScript)

## **Professional experience**

- 2015-Present, Codemasters, Audio programmer Dirt Rally Rewrote early audio reflections system. Vehicle audio.
- 2014-2015, Codemasters, Unity programmer Undisclosed Joined prototype team as sole programmer working on two game ideas based around user generated content and AI using Behaviour Trees.
- 2012-2014, Codemasters, Audio programmer GRID Autosport Revamped audio damage systems, audio system optimisations, implemented hot

Phone: (+44) 07910-390 599 Webpage: <a href="http://www.hentula.com">http://www.hentula.com</a> Email: <a href="joakim.hentula@gmail.com">joakim.hentula@gmail.com</a>

Joakim Hentula 4 Hitchman Mews CV31 3QW Leamington Spa, Warwickshire United Kingdom

reload solution for audio data.

- 2011-2012, Codemasters, Audio programmer GRID 2 Created audio mark up tool with real time in game editing, assisted in integrating 3rd party audio middleware.
- 2010-2011, Codemasters, Audio programmer DiRT: Showdown Joined audio programming team as sole audio programmer for the game, using in house audio solution.
- 2009 2010, Codemasters, Game programmer DiRT3

  Created a data driven component based game system with support for replay and network serialisation. Prototyped and developed USP Gymkhana game mode.
- 2008 2009, Codemasters, Game programmer Colin McRae: DiRT2 Created the career progression system, several game modes and a framework enabling game code to support both local and networked play.
- 2007 2008, Codemasters, Game programmer RaceDriver: GRID Created ghost-lap recording/playback system and PC installer, refactored save systems, integrated Games For Windows..

#### **Achievements**

Created component based game object system supporting replay and network serialisation. The system has subsequently been used by multiple teams on multiple projects.

### **Education**

2004 - 2007, University of Skövde - Computer Game Development - Programming (Degree of Bachelor of Science with a major in Computer Science)

## Languages

Swedish (native), English (fluent)

#### References

References will be supplied on request.

## **Example of previous projects**

Please visit http://www.hentula.com for example projects.